

# Peer Christensen

**Data Scientist** 

Researcher in cognitive science with 5+ years experience quantifying patterns in human behaviour and various other types of data. Passionate about statistics and programming, unraveling and communicating insights from complex data and improving my skill set along the way. Organizer of monthly seminars on statistics, data science and R at Lund University.

Copenhagen, Denmark

in dk.linkedin.com/in/peer-christensen-datascientist

+45 5357 1604

peerchristensen.netlify.com

github.com/PeerChristensen

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Researcher** Lund University

08/2014 - Present

Tasks & achievements

- Developed and conducted five behavioral studies using Python
- Wrangled, analyzed and visualized data in R
- Given eight tutorials to colleagues on statistics and programming in R and Python
- Communicated key research findings at conferences and in scientific journals

# Research assistant

**Aarhus University** 

08/2009 - 01/2013

Tasks & achievements

- Helped design and develop more than six studies
- Collected data using various technologies
- Contributed to four high-impact research papers

#### **EDUCATION**

### **PhD student in Cognitive science** Lund University

2014 – Present

Selected PhD courses

- Machine learning
- Advanced statistical methods in R
- Text analytics
- Python for developing experiments

## MA in Cognitive semiotics

**Aarhus University** 

2010 - 2013

## **BA in Linguistics**

Aarhus University & Radboud University Nijmegen

2006 - 2009

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

R	Python	Machine learning			Text mining
Data visualisation			Tableau	SQ	L

#### RECENT DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS

Applied topic modelling and sentiment analysis to extract customer insights from thousands of reviews of various businesses

Built software packages for extracting customer reviews from three major product review sites

Performed PCA and cluster analyses on socio-economic factors to help a Danish municipality distribute DKK 165M to public schools

Modeled human performance in reaction time tasks using mixed-effects regression

Created interactive maps based on geotagged data extracted from Google Trends, WHO and mobile devices

Customer analytics - e.g. segmentation, A/B testing and churn prediction on large datasets

### **LANGUAGES**

English				
Danish				
French				0
Swedish				0
Italian		0	0	0
German		0	0	0